## ANDY CHEN

Rich experience in full-stack software engineering with full product life-cycle and open source contribution. I care about user experience as much as internal/external developer experience, with multiple experiences in working with a cross-functional team. Currently earned AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate.

amazingandyyy@gmail.com github.com/amazingandyyy https://amazingandyyy.com linkedin.com/in/amazingandyyy

#### **EXPERIENCE**

<u>Blockchain Node Service Inc.</u>, San Francisco — Founder and Project Lead Developer July 2018 - PRESENT

- Leveraged Docker, AWS CloudFormation to speed up the full-node initial process, successfully decrease the usual full-node hosting DevOps from 3 weeks to 15 seconds.
- Distribute stable service globally with CloudFront and Route53, successfully cut server usage by 60% and decrease responding time by 50%.
- Developed a serverless, stateless architecture to deliver the first-of-its-kind full-node monitoring service and won the top 3 as "the most fundable project" on Draper Demo day in Fall 2018.

<u>Ventured International Inc.</u>, San Francisco — *Lead Engineer* turned *Chief Product Officer* July 2017 - April 2018 (company resolved)

- Co-authored whitepaper and designed and developed the whole end-to-end DApp from zero-to-one in less than a month.
- Implemented TDD with Jest to engineer production-ready smart contracts in Solidity and deployed to Ethereum Live Network with Truffle framework.
- Launched ERC20 VentureCoin(VCN) token and released a 3-month crowd-sale in November 2017.

### **Bodhi Project**, San Mateo— *Software Engineer* May 2018 - Oct. 2018

- Refactored the whole React UI library from redux to mobX architecture in 4 weeks and successfully initiated the migration from electron-based to browser-based DApp which ultimately led to an increase in usage by 2 times.
- Developed and audited production-ready complex smart contracts on QTUM blockchain.
- Introduced style-checking linter and coordinated with teammates to improve the collaboration cycle and speed up the dev.
- Built the prototype for ginfura, a full node service for QTUM ecosystem.

<u>Yeah Education Group</u>, Berkeley — *Chief Technical Officer* Dec. 2015 - April 2017

• Led a cross-timezone development team to migrate the full-stack app

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Javascript, **Nodejs**, **Golang**, Python, **Solidity** 

Front-End: HTML/SCSS, Javascript,

React/Redux/MobX, Webpack, RWD

Backend: RESTful, GraphQL, Express, NoSQL, SQL, Nextjs, SSR, SEO, JWT

DevOps: npm, **Docker/K8S**, TravisCl, **AWS SAA**, **Truffle** 

# OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

**Vechain/thorify,** update documentation and suggest [#8 closed] new thorify features

amazingandyyy/mern-stack, open source my mern stack boilerplate repo and gained 14 forks and participants

nodejs/node, submitted
PR#10092[merged] and
#10093[merged] to update and
improve testing environment

dawsbot/mailto, submitted PR#3[closed], PR#4[merged] to resolve multiple issues and optimize key features

- from angular 1.6 to React 15 in 3 months and migrate RESTful API to GraphQL hybrid API.
- The software-based solution successfully scaled the business 20 times to 2M annual revenue in 2016 and led the company to join Berkeley-owned Skydeck incubator and push the company to become UC Berkeley's only official admission partner.

# <u>Andysign Studio</u>, Mountain View — *Freelance Software Engineer* Oct 2014 - Sept. 2016

- Coordinated with 8 clients to develop websites including Groove Trend and Swallet, and Taiwanese Volunteer Group with about 1K daily visitors.
- Implemented A/B testing for UI elements, heatmap analysis on user behaviors and website SEO leading to a 100% increase in traffic and earned 95% satisfaction rate from clients.

#### **EDUCATION**

# <u>Draper University</u>, San Mateo — *Certificated Startup Hero* Sept 2018 - Oct 2018

Grow <u>venode</u> project into <u>BNS</u> and graduated at top 3 as "the most fundable project" voted by hundreds of VCs on Demo Day, completed Hero Training Program and is nominated as "the most positive student" by Tim Draper

# <u>University of California, Berkeley</u>, Berkeley — *Bachelor's of Science, Cognitive Science* June 2016 - July 2018

The first and only student completing all 3 blockchain courses (Blockchain for Developers, Blockchain Lab, Blockchain Fundamental).

Certificate in Entrepreneurship & Technology from SCET and served as Tech Chair in Senior Class Council 18. Completed courses included Data Vis., Computer HCI, Cognitive Science, Linguistics, Data Structure, Discrete Math and Machine Learning.

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Leptin** — A PoW cryptocurrency implement in Nodejs

Designed and Built a whole cryptocurrency in Nodejs with leveraging the power of WebRTC, LevelDB, hyperlogs to build a peer-to-peer blockchain implementing Proof-of-work, secp256k1 and dynamical difficulty.

### <u>Etherbrite</u> — An Eventbrite-like DApp.

Built a DApp in Solidity, TruffleJS, Web3js and React/Redux. From deploying events on smart contract to register and check-in.

## **VRPlayer** — A video player built with ReactVR and openGL

Built this video player on the fist of ReactVR's launch, with a focus on the interaction details of user experience in virtual reality.

#### HACKATHONS/AWARDS

H4YT Blockchain Hackathon 2018 - **No.1 nomination by Cosmos** for building <u>Celadon</u>, a lotionjs middleware donating money to help our environment.

LAUNCH Hackathon 2016 - **1st place of Uber Challenge** [2016] for building <u>Teleport</u>, an advertisement site that magically delivers customers to your door.

AT&T loT Hackathon - **Best Mobile App and loT Solution Overall**[2015] for building
Connect, a radio player controlled by a gesture controller, Myo.

#### MENTORSHIP/GLOG

# **Distributed system Salon** authored a technical blog sharing a series of tutorials on web development, smart contract, DevOps and software design topics.

# **DIDX/Vechain Blockchain Community Group on Github** I initiative virtual organization on Github to discuss topics of developer experience and developer tools.

NodeSchool Oakland and San Francisco Chapter Served as regular monthly mentor in Nodeschool Oakland

**Reactathon, 2017** Served as a mentor at the hackathon held by the Real World React organization